It all began on New Year's Day...
整个故事始于元旦那一天
in my 32nd year of being single.
我32岁仍然小姑独处
Once again I found myself on my own...
每年都是孤家寡人
and going to my mother's annual turkey curry buffet.
到老妈家吃咖哩火鸡自助餐
Every year she tries to fix me up with some bushy-haired, middle-aged bore...
而每年她都要为我找一些 头发茂盛的中年男子
and I feared this year would be no exception.
相信今年也不例外
There you are, dumpling.
你来啦
My mum, a strange creature...
我妈是个怪人
from the time when a gherkin was still the height of sophistication.
似乎来自古早年代
- Doilies, Pam? Hello, Bridget. - Third drawer from the top, Una...
潘，茶杯垫呢？哈罗，布丽姬
By the way, the Darcys are here.
达西夫妇也来了
They brought Mark with them.
还把马克带来
- Ah, here we go. - You remember Mark.
又来啦 你该记得马克吧
You used to play in his paddling pool. He's a barrister, very well off.
你常在他的浅池里玩水 现在他是个名律师
No, I don't remember.
我不记得他
He's divorced, apparently.
他离婚了
His wife was Japanese. Very cruel race. Now, what are you going to put on?
太太是日本人，冷漠的民族 你要穿什么衣服？
- This. - Don't be silly, Bridget.
就是这身 拜托啦
You'll never get a boyfriend if you look like you've wandered out of Auschwitz.
穿得像集中营里的犯人 难怪交不到男朋友
Run upstairs. Laid out something lovely on your bed.
到楼上去 把我替你准备的衣服穿上
Great. I was wearing a carpet.
我穿得像条花地毯一样
Here she is. My little Bridget.
我的小布丽姬来了
- Hi, Uncle Geoffrey. - Have a drink?
嗨，杰佛瑞叔叔 要酒吗？
- Come on, then. - Actually, not my uncle.
来呀 其实他不是我叔叔
Someone who insists I call him "Uncle" while he gropes my ass...
是个爱偷摸我屁股 却要我叫他叔叔的怪人
and asks me the question dreaded by all singletons.
爱问些我最怕听的问题
So, how's your love life?
爱情生活怎么样？
Super. Thanks, Uncle G.
太棒了，谢谢叔叔的关心
Still no fellow, then, eh? All right, then.
还是没有男朋友？
You career girls can't put it off forever, you know.
你们职业妇女不能再拖了
Tick-tock, tick-tock.
时间不多啦
- Hello, Dad. - Hello, darling.
哈罗，爹地 嗨，乖孩子
- How's it going? - Torture.
近来好吗？ 恐怖
Your mother's trying to fix you up with some divorce.
你妈想替你 和一个离婚的男人牵线
Human rights barrister. Pretty nasty beast, apparently.
一个人权律师，挺讨人厌的
Ding-dong.
哇！叮
Maybe this time Mum had got it right.
说不定这次老妈会误打正着
Come on. Why don't we see if Mark fancies a gherkin.
来，我们去见见马克
Good luck.
祝你好运
Maybe this was the mysterious Mr. Right...
也许他…
I'd been waiting my whole life to meet.
就是我寻觅已久的白马王子
You remember Bridget.
你该记得布丽姬
Maybe not.
也许不是
She used to run around your lawn with no clothes on, remember?
她常赤身露体在你家草地上跑
No, not as such.
不，不记得了
Come and look at your gravy, Pam. I think it's going to need sieving.
潘，快来看肉汁 好像需要过滤
Of course it doesn't need sieving. Just stir it, Una.
吴娜，不用过滤，搅搅就行了
Yes, of course. I'll be right there. Sorry. Lumpy gravy calls.
好，我就过去看看 肉汁在召唤了
- So.
那么…那么？
Are you staying at your parents' for New Year?
你会留在父母家过元旦？
- Yes. You? - Oh, no, no.
会，你呢？我不会
I was in London at a party last night...
昨晚我在伦敦参加派对
so I'm afraid I'm a bit hung over.
到今天酒还没醒
Wish I could by lying with my head in a toilet like all normal people.
真希望能在马桶上吐个痛快
New Year's resolution: Drink less. Oh, and quit smoking.
我的新年新希望 就是少喝、戒烟
And keep New Year's resolutions.
而且一定要做到
And stop talking total nonsense to strangers.
还有不对陌生人胡说八道
In fact, stop talking full stop.
最好是根本就不说话
Yes, well, perhaps it's time to eat.
很好，大概要吃饭了
Apparently she lives just around the corner from you.
她住得离你很近
Mother, I do not need a blind date.
妈妈，你别替我乱相亲
Particularly not with some verbally incontinent spinster...
尤其是那些说话不经大脑
who smokes like a chimney, drinks like a fish and dresses like her mother.
既抽烟又酗酒 穿着毫无品味的女人
Yummy. Turkey curry. My favorite.
真好吃，我最喜欢咖哩火鸡
And that was it. Right there.
就在此地
Right there. That was the moment.
就在此时
I suddenly realized that unless something changed soon...
终于觉悟了，除非我有所改变
I was going to live a life where my major relationship...
否则酒将成为我的终生伴侣
and I'd finally die fat and alone...
最后变得又丑又胖
and be found three weeks later half-eaten by Alsatians.
死后三星期 被狗吃掉一半才被人发现
Or I was about to turn into Glenn Close in Fatal Attraction.
不然就像 致命吸引力中的葛伦萝丝
All by myself
独自一人
Don't want to be
我不想
Anymore
独自一人
You have no messages.
你没有电话留言
When I was young
当我年轻时
I never needed anyone
从不需要任何人
And makin'love was just for fun
做爱只为取乐
Those days are gone
那些日子已不存在
All by myself
独自一人
Don't want to be
我不想
Anymore
独自一人
And so I made a major decision.
我做了个决定
I had to make sure that next year I wouldn't end up shit-faced...
明年不能像今年这么猪头
and listening to sad FM, easy listening for the over-30s.
只听调频台给三十岁以上的人 所准备的伤感老歌
I decided to take control of my life and start a diary...
为了掌握命运我决定写日记 “体重136磅”
to tell the truth about BridgetJones, the whole truth.
记录着真正的布丽姬 “烟量42支，酒精50单位”
Resolution number one: Obviously we'll lose 20 pounds.
第一，要减肥20磅
Number two: Always put last night's pants in the laundry basket.
第二，要把昨夜穿的内裤 放在洗衣篮里
Equally important, will find nice, sensible boyfriend to go out with...
同等重要的是 找个温柔体帖的男友
and not continue to form romantic attachments to any of the following:
不能再和以下的人深交
Alcoholics, workaholics, commitment phobics...
嗜酒如命、工作狂 结婚恐惧症
Peeping Toms, megalomaniacs, emotional fuckwits or perverts.
偷窥狂、夸大狂、爱情白痴 或是性饥渴
And especially will not fantasize about a particular person...
并且不去幻想认识那个 “一月一日星期六”
who embodies all these things.
具有以上所有特性的男人
Unfortunately, he just happens to be my boss...
不幸的，他就是我的老板
editor in chief Daniel Cleaver, and for various slightly unfair reasons...
总编辑丹尼尔
I suspect he does not fantasize about me.
我料想他对我一点兴趣也没有
Can't live
我不能
Livin'is without you
活在没有你的生活中
- Can't give anymore - Or maybe I'm wrong.
活在没有施予的日子里 也许我错了
- Happy New Year, Mr. Fitzherbert. - Happy New Year, Brenda.
费先生，新年快乐 布丽达，新年好
Mr. Fitzherbert. "Titspervert,"more like.
费先生是个窥波狂 也是丹尼尔的上司
Daniel's boss stares at my breasts with no idea who I am or what I do.
他只知猛盯我的胸部看 却不知道我的名字
Morning. I need that Kafka's Motorbike release by 11:00.
早，“卡夫卡摩托车” 要在11点发布新书促销新闻
Perpetua.
至于派楚拉
Slightly senior, and therefore thinks she's in charge of me.
比我早一点进公司 所以自认是我的上司
Most of the time I just want to staple things to her head.
我的愿望就是 把钉书针钉到她头上去
- Publicity. - All I asked...
宣传部 我只要…
I only asked if he wanted to come on a minibreak to Paris.
我只要他陪我去巴黎渡周末
Daily call from Jude. Best friend.
是茱蒂的电话
Head of investment at Brightlings Bank who spends most of her time...
她是柏特凌银行的投资主管 也是我的好朋友
trapped in the ladies'toilet crying over fuckwit boyfriend.
多数时间 躲在厕所为男朋友哭泣
Am I too needy? Am I codependent?
我太穷、太不独立吗？
No, you're not. It's not you.
你当然不是
You're lovely. It's vile Richard.
你很可爱，都是卑鄙李察的错
He's just a big knobhead with no knob.
他是个没种的混蛋
Is some people's opinion of Kafka...
那只是某些人 对卡夫卡这本书的意见
but they couldn't be more wrong.
可是他们错了
This book is a searing vision of the wounds our century has inflicted...
这本书深刻描述着
on traditional masculinity.
本世纪男子气概遭受打击
It's positively Vonnegutesque.
的确是当代的好书
Thank you for calling, Professor Leavis.
谢谢你李维斯教授
Guest list for launch party.
这是新书出版会的客人名单
F.R. Leavis?
李维斯？
Wow.
哇！
The F.R. Leavis who wrote Mass Civilization and Minority Culture?
就是写大众文明 和少数民族文化的那个李维斯
The F.R. Leavis who died in 1978?
那位死于1978年的李维斯？
Amazing.
太不可思议
Emergency summit with urban family...
四巨头紧急会议
for coherent discussion of career crisis.
讨论工作危机
Fuck 'em. Fuck the lot of them.
去他的，去他的头
Tell them they can stick fucking Leavis up their fucking asses.
去他的李维斯 告诉他们去死
Good, good. That's very useful.
不错，很有帮助
Shazzer, journalist. Likes to say "fuck"a lot.
沙嘉是记者，喜欢说去他的
Jude, what would you do if one of your assistants...
茱蒂，如果你的助理 犯了这种小错，你会怎么样？
- I'd fire you, Bridge. - Excellent.
我会开除你 你这是帮倒忙
Is that Cleaver chap still as cute as ever?
丹尼尔还是那么英俊？
Oh, God, yes.
是呀
Then I think a well-timed blow job is probably the best answer.
我想及时的口交应该有帮助
- Oh, you love it. - Are you the chap that sang that song?
是你想得要死！ 你就是那个歌星吗？
Yes. Yes, I am.
没错
Tom, '80s pop icon who only wrote one hit record...
汤姆，八零年代的歌星 只写了一首畅销曲就退休
then retired because he found that one record was quite enough...
因为他发现这足够 让他在九零年代
to get him laid for the whole of the '90s.
得到充分的性满足
- Well, great song. - Thank you. Thank you so much.
真是首好歌 非常谢谢你
- Total poof, of course. - More vodka?
不错，他是同性恋 还要伏特加吗？
- No! - Yes! Fill her up, goddamn it!
不要！ 替她装满
At least now I'm in my 30s, I can hold my drink.
好在我已进入三十大关 身体对酒精已有了抗体
- Oops! - Mind the step.
唉哟！ 小心一阶
She's fine. Drive on.
她没事，开车吧
Apparently F.R. Leavis is coming.
李维斯似乎要来参加
Afternoon, Bridget.
布丽姬，你早呀
What do you mean you're going on holiday?
什么，你要去渡假？
What aboutJulia?
那茱丽亚呢？
We've got a problem with the Teddy Knows Best campaign.
“泰迪最知道” 的新书宣传活动有了问题
The only problem is the kitchen.
症结是场地
- There isn't room to swing a cat. - Message Mr. Cleaver.
场地实在太小了
Am appalled by message.
被你的电子邮件吓了一跳
Skirt is demonstrably neither sick nor absent.
裙子没生病、也没缺席
Appalled by management's blatantly size-ist attitude to skirt.
管理阶层对裙子的偏执 使我感到惊骇
Suggest management sick, not skirt!
裙子没病，是管理阶层病了
Right. Yeah.
好的
No, I understand that. I understand that perfectly.
我了解，非常了解
Very bad start to the year.
今年的开始似乎不太好
Have been seduced by informality of messaging medium...
先被电子邮件引诱
into flirting with office scoundrel.
又和公司的流氓调情
Will persevere with resolution to find a nice, sensible man.
本来新年新计划 是找个温柔体帖的男人
Will put a stop to flirting... first thing tomorrow.
看来调情一定要停止 明天一早就办
Good plan.
就这么决定
If walking past office was attempt to demonstrate presence of skirt...
如果故意走过我的办公室 是要证明你穿了裙子
can only say that it has failed parlously... Cleave.
那你完全失败了－丹尼尔
Shut up, please. I am very busy and important.
闭嘴，本小姐既忙又重要
P.S. How dare you sexually harass me in this impertinent manner?
又及：你怎可用这种 不礼貌的方式给我性骚扰
MessageJones. Mortified to have caused offense.
给布丽姬的电子邮件 非常抱歉触怒了你
Will avoid all non-P.C. Overtones in future. Deeply apologetic.
一定避开所有的不当言行 在此深深悔过
P.S. Like your tits in that top.
又及： 喜欢你的巨波而不是上衣
Mustn't read too much into it, though.
不能太沉迷于此
And it all began, of course, with some very irresponsible E-mailing...
这一切都是由布丽姬那条
over Bridget's nonexistent skirt.
不存在裙子的电子邮件开始
- The New York office for you. - Yeah. Tell 'em I'll get back to 'em.
纽约办公室找你 告诉他们我等会儿和他们联络
- Evening, Kenneth. - Evening.
肯尼士，晚安 晚安
If you've got a moment, I'd like a word before you leave.
在你离开前，我想和你谈谈
Yes, certainly.
没问题
- I'll see you in a sec. - Excellent.
等会儿见 好的
- And, Brenda? - Yes.
布丽达 什么事？
At the Kafka's Motorbike thing, thought it might be fun...
在“卡夫卡摩托车” 新书促销会上
if you introduce me before I introduce him.
由你介绍我，再由我介绍他 可能比较生动
Add a lovely sense of occasion.
会给现场加点轻松的气氛
Certainly, sir.
没问题
- What are you doing tonight? - Actually, I'm busy.
你今晚有计划吗？ 我会很忙
Right. Well, that's a shame. I just...
噢，真可惜，我想…
I thought it might be a charitable thing to take your skirt out for dinner...
我本想发个慈悲 带你的裙子去吃饭
and try and fatten it up a bit.
把它喂胖一点
Maybe you could come too.
你也可以一起来
- What about tomorrow? - No.
明天好吗？ 不行
- Tomorrow's the launch. - Yes, of course.
明天是新书促销活动 喔，对呀！
Possibly the worst book ever published.
可能是史上最糟的书 “本世纪最伟大的杰作”
Well, in the end, that's not the ad line we've gone for.
我们的广告标语好像不是这样
- Next night. - Let's see, shall we?
再下一个晚上呢 到时再说吧！
'Night, Daniel.
晚安，丹尼尔
Right. No pressure, Bridge, but your whole future happiness...
对，不要给自己太多压力
now depends on how you behave on this one social occasion.
未来的幸福 就看你现在怎么处理了
- Right. What shall I do? - First, look gorgeous.
那我该怎么做？ 第一，要打扮得很漂亮
Two: Then totally ignore Daniel and suck up to famous authors.
第二，要忽视丹尼尔 尽量讨好那些名作家
Salman.
塞门
Circulate...
会周旋
oozing intelligence.
有深度
Isn't it terrible about Chechnya?
俄国的暴动实在可怕…
Introduce people with thoughtful details, such as:
要细心的替人介绍，例如
Sheila, this is Daniel. Daniel, this is Sheila.
希拉，这是丹尼尔 丹尼尔，这是希拉
Sheila enjoys horse riding and comes from New Zealand.
希拉来自纽西兰，喜欢骑马
Daniel enjoys publishing and comes...
丹尼尔从事出版业
- All over your face? - Exactly.
喜欢玩弄女性 不错
Excuse me. I'm terribly sorry to interrupt you when you're having dinner.
对不起 在晚餐时间打扰你实在很抱歉
- It's just that... - Yes. Yes, it was me.
只是… 不错，是我
Yes. Nine years ago.
那是九年以前的事
No current plans to record anything else.
现在没有出唱片的打算
- Thank you so much. - It's just that...
谢谢你 只是…
your chair is on my wife's coat.
你的椅子压到我太太的外套了
- Your chair. - Of course it is.
你的椅子 噢，是的
- I'm so terribly sorry. - Thank you.
实在太对不起 谢谢
Major dilemma.
我该怎么做
If I actually do, by some terrible chance, end up in flagrante...
在我向性爱投降的情况下
surely these would be most attractive at crucial moment.
它才能发出致命的诱惑力
However, chances of reaching crucial moment greatly increase...
反过来说，当情欲高涨时
by wearing these scary stomach-holding-in pants...
穿上这条老奶奶的束腹裤
very popular with grannies the world over.
他恐怕马上就胃口全失
Tricky. Very tricky.
真是难以选择
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to...
各位先生女士 在此向大家推荐
the launch of Kafka's Motorbike, the greatest book of our time.
本世纪最伟大的杰作 “卡夫卡摩托车”终于发行了
And here to introduce it is Mr. Titspervert.
现在为大家介绍窥波狂
Fitzherbert, Fitzherbert.
是费先生，费先生
Circulate, oozing intelligence.
会周旋、有深度
Ignore Daniel and be fabulous with everyone else.
忽视丹尼尔，和别人谈笑风声
I am the intellectual equal of everyone else here.
我的智商和大家都一样
It's like a whole theory of short fiction and of the novella.
它就像短篇小说的原理一样
And, of course, the problem with Martin's definition of the novella...
但马丁对短篇故事的定义
is that it really only applies to him.
似乎只适用于他自己
That doesn't sound like Martin. Not.
这和马丁不太像，真的不像
Do you know...
你知道…
where the toilets are?
厕所在哪里吗？
Stay calm. Can't get any worse.
镇定，不会比这更糟了
- What are you doing here? - I've been asking myself that question.
你来这里做什么？ 我也在问自己
I came with a colleague. So how are you?
我和同事一起来的，你好吗？
Well, apart from being very disappointed...
很失望 没看到你穿那件驯鹿的毛衣
Anyone going to introduce me?
替我介绍一下？
Introduce people with thoughtful details.
细心的替人介绍
Perpetua, this is Mark Darcy.
派楚拉，这位是马克
Mark's a prematurely middle-aged prick with a cruel-raced ex-wife.
马克是中年白痴，早熟 有个冷漠的前妻
Perpetua's a fat-ass old bag who spends her time bossing me around.
派楚拉是个 一天到晚管我闲事的老女人
Maybe not.
这样不好
Anyone going to introduce me?
替我介绍一下？
This is Mark Darcy.
这位是马克
Mark's a top barrister. He comes from Grafton Underwood.
马克是名律师在城里上班
Perpetua is one of my work colleagues.
这位是派楚拉，是我同事
I know you by reputation, of course.
你的声望很高
Natasha.
娜塔沙
This is BridgetJones. Bridget, this is Natasha.
这位是布丽姬，这位是娜塔沙
Natasha is a top attorney and specializes in family law.
娜塔沙是名律师专精家庭法
Bridget works in publishing and used to play naked in my paddling pool.
布丽姬在出版社上班 爱到我的浅池里裸泳
How odd.
奇怪的嗜好
- Perpetua, how's the house hunt going? - Disaster.
派楚拉，房子看得如何？ 一塌胡涂
Can't even go into it with you.
谈都别谈
By the by, that man is gorgeous.
那个男的很英俊
Yes, Mark.
的确不错
Just give me time. Give me time.
给我点时间，一定叫他上钩
You've written "a searing vision"... Can you remember the rest of this?
除了深刻描述外 你还记得其它吗？
"Of the wounds our century has inflicted on traditional masculinity.
谈到本世纪男子气概遭受打击
Positively Vonnegutesque."
的确是当代的佳作
Listen, you don't know where the loos are here, do you?
你知道厕所在哪里吗？
- Yes. They're that way. - Thanks.
就在那边 谢谢
One, two.
一、二
Ladies and gentlemen.
各位先生女士们
Ladies and...
各位…
Sorry, the...
抱歉
mike's not working.
麦克风坏了
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生女士们
welcome to the launch of Kafka's Motorbike...
欢迎来到“卡夫卡摩托车” 的新书促销会场
the greatest book of our time.
是本世纪最伟大的杰作
Obviously, except for your books, Mr. Rushdie...
当然你的书除外，鲁斯施先生
which are also very good.
它很棒
And Lord Archer.
还有安契尔爵士
Yours aren't bad either.
你的书也不坏
Anyway, what I mean is...
好了，我要说的是
welcome, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎各位
Thank you for coming to the launch...
来到这个促销活动
of one of the top 30 books of our time.
是为当代名列 前三十名之一的著作所举办
Anyway. At least.
至少是前三十名
And here to introduce it properly...
现在我正式请一位先生
is the man we all call...
来郑重介绍本书 我们称他为…
- Titspervert. - Mister...
窥波狂
Because that is his name.
因为这就是他的名字
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you, Brenda.
谢谢你，布丽达
Just switch this on.
只要转这里麦克风就能用
So how autobiographical is your work, Salman?
塞门，你的自传进度如何？
It's an amazing thing. Nobody's ever asked me that question.
非常好，你是第一个问起
Excuse me.
失陪了
Jones, sod 'em all. It was a brilliant...
布丽姬，不要泄气 你讲得很好
postmodernist masterpiece of oratorical fireworks, really.
带有后现代主义派的风范
You're looking very sexy, Jones.
你看起来很性感
I'm going to have to take you to dinner now whether you like it or not, okay?
不管你同不同意 我坚持请你去吃饭
Come on. Get your stuff.
走，去拿你的外套
How do you feel about this situation in Chechnya? Isn't it a nightmare?
你对俄国的暴动有何感想？ 真可怕
I couldn't give a fuck, Jones. Now look.
那干我屁事，布丽姬，我问你
How do you know Arsey Darcy?
你认识马克吗？
Apparently I used to run 'round naked in his paddling pool.
以前我爱在他的浅池里裸泳
I bet you did, you dirty bitch.
我就知道你很淫荡
- What about you? - Same.
你呢？也一样
I was best man at his wedding.
我是他的男傧相
- He was a mate from Cambridge. - Then what?
我们是剑桥大学的同学 接着呢？
Then nothing.
没啦
You don't need to protect him. He's no friend of mine.
你不用保护他 他并不是我的朋友
Well, then, many years later...
多年之后
I made the somewhat catastrophic mistake...
我犯了一个不可饶恕的错误
of introducing him to my fiancee.
就是把他介绍给我的未婚妻
And...
我必须承认
I couldn't say in all honesty I've ever quite forgiven him.
至今仍旧不能原谅他
God. So...
天呀，看来…
he's a nasty bastard as well as a dull bastard.
他既龌龊又沉闷
Yes. Yes, I think that's fair.
对，他的确是这样
Anyway, fuck him. Listen, don't let him ruin our evening.
好了，不谈他 省得扫了今晚的兴
Why don't you have some more wine...
你再来点酒
and tell me more about practicing French kissing with girls at school?
告诉我你在学校 和女孩接吻的事
- That's a very good story. - It wasn't French kissing.
一定很刺激 并没有用舌头
Don't care. Make it up. That's an order, Jones.
不管，我命令你捏造一个
So, how about a drink at my place?
到我那喝一杯，好吗？
Totally innocent, no funny business, just full sex.
很单纯，只有性 保证没有不道德的事
I should get a taxi.
我该叫计程车
But thank you for the lovely dinner.
谢谢你这顿愉快的晚餐
It's a pleasure, Jones.
是我的荣幸
You're alone all the time
当你独自徘徊
Does it ever bother you
你曾不安过
Have you asked why
是何原由
You seem to fall in love
你曾爱过
And out again
也失恋过
Do you really ever love
是真正爱过
Orjust pretend
或佯装有过
Baby, why fool yourself
宝贝，不必自欺
Don't be afraid to help yourself
帮助自己何惧之有
Now, these are very silly little boots, Jones.
布丽姬，这是双奇怪的靴子
And this is a very silly little dress...
这是一件奇怪的衣服
and these are...
还有这是…
fuck me... absolutely enormous pants.
天呀，这么大的裤子
- Jesus. Fuck. - No. Don't apologize. I like them.
要命！ 别道歉，我很喜欢它
Hello, Mummy!
哈罗，妈咪！
I have to have another look. They're too good to be true.
我得再看一次，太难得了
Nothing to be embarrassed about.
没什么好尴尬的
I'm wearing something similar myself. Here. I'll show you.
我穿的也差不多，你看
This time decide that you will open up
这次你决定放开胸怀
Let it in
接受它
There's no shame in sharing love
分享爱情并不可耻 “体重131磅，以性代替食物”
You feel within
“烟量22支，性爱后来根烟” 你感觉到它的存在
So jump right in
进来吧
Head over heels
完全地
That was fantastic.
真棒
What happens at the office?
在公司怎么办？
I'm glad you asked that. You see...
我很高兴你问了
it's a publishing house, so that means people write things for us...
这是一间出版社 表示作家写稿给我们
and then we print out all the pages and fasten them together...
我们印好装订成册
and make them into what we call a "book,"Jones.
这就是所谓的书
Do you think people will notice?
人们会注意到吗？
- Notice what? - Us.
注意到什么？我们
Working together, sleeping together.
一起工作，一起睡觉
Hang on a minute, Jones.
等一等
Just slow down. It started on Tuesday, and now it's Thursday.
慢点，我们是星期二开始的 现在才星期四
It's not exactly a long-term relationship yet, is it?
恋情尚短，不能算是长期恋爱
You very bad man.
你很坏
BridgetJones, wanton sex goddess...
布丽姬性爱女神
with a very bad man between her thighs.
要和坏男人发生性行为
Mum.
妈妈
It's a truth universally acknowledged...
这是个不变的真理
that the moment one area of your life starts going okay...
当生命的某方面好转时
another part of it falls spectacularly to pieces.
另一方面就会出差错
Anyone else want to have it oeuf? Don't be shy, madam.
女士们，谁要买蛋白，别害羞
French.
这是法文
Have it oeuf with the WiseCrack Egg Peeler.
用俏皮蛋白分离器来取得蛋白
Now, nice, firm grip.
稳稳的握住
Put it in the hole.
把蛋放在洞里
Up, down, up, down, and off it comes in your hand.
上上下下，就到你手中
Mind the overspray. Sorry.
小心一起出来的液体 抱歉
Darling, if I came in with my knickers on my head, he wouldn't notice.
就算我把内裤穿在头上 他也不会注意到
I've spent 35 years cleaning his house...
三十五年来 我整理他的房子
washing his clothes, bringing up his children.
洗他的衣服，带他的孩子
I'm your child too.
我也是你的孩子
To be honest, darling, having children isn't all it's cracked up to be.
老实说 有孩子不是什么高兴的事
Given my chance again, I'm not sure I'd have any.
若让我从头来起 我一定不要孩子
Now it's the winter of my life, and I haven't actually got anything of my own.
现在我已是垂暮之年 却从没有过自己的生活
I've got no power, no real career...
我没权力、没事业
no sex life.
更没性生活
Got no life at all. I'm like the grasshopper who sang all summer.
根本就没有人生 我像蚱蜢一样没有未来
- Like Germaine sodding Geer. - Greer.
就像变性女作家洁玫葛儿 是葛丽儿
Well, anyway, I'm not having it.
反正我不要再忍耐
And I've been talent-spotted.
而且电视经纪看上我
Julian thinks I've got great potential.
朱利安说我有潜力
- Who's Julian? - From the Home Shopping Channel.
朱利安是谁？ 他主持家中购物频道
Comes into the store to have his colors done.
他到店里来做色彩分析
Potential for what?
哪方面的潜力？
As a demonstrator on his cable show... you know, his assistant.
做他电视示范节目的助手
Apparently, it's the highest-rated show on the channel.
他的收视率最高
Apart from the one with the fat people who beat up their relatives.
和那些谈论 敏感话题的节目不同
I must whiz. Have you heard from Mark Darcy?
我得走了，你见过马克吗？
Good-bye, Mum.
妈妈，再见
And a few weeks later, it got lots worse.
几个礼拜后情况更糟
- Hello! - Look at this.
哈罗！你来看
...hanging off this heart-shaped pendant.
吊着心形垂饰
One of my own personal recommendations...
我所要特别推荐的是
is this absolutely stunning matching necklace and earring set.
这套耳环与项 真是美极了
The earrings, measuring just over a centimeter...
耳环只有一公分宽
in genuine diamante with topaz and lapis lazuli...
将钻石、黄玉和青金石
in a lovely mock-gold finish.
镶在美丽的合金坐台上
The exact replica of those worn at Wimbledon in 1993...
同样的首饰，肯特伯爵夫人
by Her Royal Highness, the Duchess of Kent.
曾在1993年的温布顿戴过
Has she actually moved out, then?
她真搬出去了？
Apparently she and this tangerine-tinted buffoon are suddenly an item.
他们俩居然热门起来
Half our friends have had them 'round to bloody dinner.
我们的朋友都争着邀他们吃饭
She's even taking jaundiced Julian to Una Alconbury's tarts and vicars party.
她还要带那个黄胆病的朱利安 参加妓女与牧师的化妆派对
That's not the Pamela I knew. That's cruel.
潘变了，她变得太残酷
Still...
可是
could be a golden opportunity.
这也许就是你的转机
If you spent the entire party...
如果整个派对 你只和别的女人调情
- Will it? - That's how I got my man.
会吗？ 我就是这样找到男朋友的
Have you got a boyfriend? A real one?
你真的交了男朋友？
I have, Father. I have.
是的，我真的有男朋友了
And he's perfect.
而且他完美得不得了
Hurrah. Am no longer tragic spinster...
哇！不再是悲惨的单身女郎
but proper girlfriend of bona fide sex god...
而是正牌性神的女朋友
so committed that he's taking me...
为了证明他的诚意
on a full-blown, minibreak holiday weekend.
他坚持带我去渡这个长周末
Promise me we don't have to sit in little boats...
你得保证不会坐在小船上
and read poncey poetry to each other.
互念淫诗做乐
He's also agreed to protect me...
他也答应在 妓女与牧师的派对上
at Uncle Geoffrey's hideous tarts and vicars party.
保护我不被杰佛瑞叔叔占便宜
This can't be just shagging. A minibreak means true love.
来渡这个假 就证明我们不只有性还有真爱
Suddenly feel like screen goddess in manner of Grace Kelly.
突然觉得我就是 银幕偶像葛莉丝凯利
Though, perhaps, ever so slightly less elegant under pressure.
可惜在压力下 是少了点她的典雅
Very quiet here, isn't it? Are we the only guests?
好安静 我们是唯一的客人吗？
We have a wedding this weekend.
周末有个婚礼
I believe there are just four of you not involved.
只有你们四个例外
You do the boats. I'll do the tea.
你去安排船，我来泡茶
- Oh, Jesus. - Hello there.
唉，真倒霉！ 嗨，你们好
Well, well.
真不错
Take it you're also heading for Alconburys' rockery.
你们也来参加妓女与牧师派对
- Yes, that's right. - I brought Natasha.
没错 我带娜塔沙一起来
Get a bit of work done. Thought I might make it a not entirely wasted weekend.
想趁机做点工作 才不会浪费整个周末
How interesting. What a gripping life you do lead.
有趣，你真会把握人生
I'll see you upstairs in a second.
我们楼上见
The weakness of their case...
他们案子的弱点
lies in the deposition they made on August 30.
是在八月三十日的证辞上
"Season of mist...
朦胧的季节
and mellow fruitlessness."
没有肥美多汁的果实
Oh, fuck me, I love Keats. Have you heard this one?
我最喜欢诗人济慈 你听过这首吗？
There was a young woman from Ealing...
来自依凌的女子
who had a peculiar feeling.
有着特殊的感觉
She lay on her back and opened her crack...
她躺下打开拉
and pissed all over the ceiling.
朝着天花板撒尿
Bollocks. Shit.
什么胡说八道
- I'm boarding you. No alternative. - Don't you dare!
我要上你的船 你敢！
- I'm king of the world! - No!
我是宇宙之王 小心！
Fuck me!
糟糕！
- Piss and bollocks. That's it. - You stupid ass!
他妈的，你也来做落汤鸡 笨蛋！
Bollocks.
混蛋
So childish.
真幼稚
- Yes. - Darce, come on in!
是的 马克，来呀！
Water's lovely.
水里很舒服
You're working too hard, mate.
你工作得太辛苦了
That thing you just did is actually illegal in several countries.
你刚刚做的事 在很多地方是不合法的
That is the major reason I'm so thrilled to be living in Britain today.
这就是我爱住在英国的原因
I can't understand why the prime minister...
我不明白为什么首相 不在他演讲稿里多提一点
- You should write to him about it. - I intend to.
你可以写信给他 我是要这么做
- Do you love me? - Shut up, or I'll do it again.
你爱我吗？
- Right. You asked for it.
这可是你自找的
And over you go.
转过去
I'm going to give you something to bite on.
我给你个可以咬住的东西
Here. Okay? Pop this in your mouth, darling.
就是这个 宝贝，把它放在嘴里
You're begging for it.
你不是想得快疯了吗
Stop it!
停止
I've got to go back to town. A meeting's come up.
我得回去开会
- On a Sunday? - The meeting's first thing tomorrow.
在星期日？ 会议是明天一早
I've got to work on some figures.
但我得先做些统计
We could just pop into the party...
我们可以去一下就走
I've got to head back.
我得立刻回去
Listen, if you've changed your mind, you could just say so.
如果你不喜欢我可以直说
Because, honestly, I don't see what could be so important.
我实在看不出会议有多重要
No, well, you wouldn't, would you?
看不出，你当然看不出
'Cause you don't have the faintest idea of how much trouble the company's in.
因为你根本不了解 公司有多大的危机
You swan in in your short skirt and your sexy see-through blouse...
你每天只顾穿着短裙 透明上衣
and fanny around with press releases.
和促销活动玩游戏
This is the Americans flying in 'cause they're thinking of shutting us down...
这次美国公司来伦敦 就是想他妈的关闭我们公司
Sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry. I'm being a prat.
抱歉，我像个白痴
I'm going to arrange a lovely car to come and pick you up...
回伦敦的车子我会安排
and take you back to London after the party, okay?
在派对结束后来接你
If you have to travel alone, travel in style.
要独自旅行就要有派头
And I also think it's very important...
况且我非常希望
that you win this costume competition.
你能赢个服装冠军回来
Good. Good start.
好，是个好的开始
Now, then, Miss Jones, where does this go?
布丽姬小姐，这该放在哪里？
Oh, well, here we go.
好，上场吧
Trying hard to fight off a vision of Mum and Auntie Una in fishnet tights.
我在想老妈和吴娜姑母 扮成妓女不知会怎样
Seems unnatural, wrong even, for 60-year-olds...
就算在星期日的下午 六十多岁的人
to dress up as prostitutes and priests on a Sunday afternoon.
打扮成妓女和牧师的模样 也很反常
Oh, holyJesus.
我的天！
- Where are the other tarts and vicars? - Didn't Geoffrey call you?
其他的妓女和牧师呢？ 杰佛瑞没通知你？
- Didn't you telephone Colin and Bridget? - How's my little Bridget?
你没通知布丽姬吗？ 我的小布丽姬，你好吗？
Where's this chap of yours?
你的男朋友呢？
- He had to work, so... - Likely tale.
他要工作，所以… 一贯的谎言
Off they run.
上完了就走
Bizarre what some men find attractive.
这样怎么会吸引男人
- Oh, God. - Darling.
天呀！ 杰佛瑞
What on earth are you wearing? You look like a common prostitute.
你穿什么衣服？ 看起来就像个妓女
- Yes, that was actually the point. - Say hi toJulian.
本来就是这个意思嘛 这是朱利安
Hello, Julian.
朱利安，你好
My dear, you and your mother could be sisters.
你和你妈就像对姐妹花
And what a lovely bracelet.
好漂亮的手镯
It's what I call an "all-rounder."
我最欣赏这种首饰
Sort of thing one can wear with anything to any occasion.
一年四季、任何场合都能戴
Have you spoken to my dad?
看到爸爸没有？
Yes. He's behaving most bizarrely.
见到了，今天特别奇怪
I think he was trying to flirt with Penny Husbands-Bosworth, poor thing.
他好像在和培妮调情
She was very frightened. She's only just had her ovaries done.
真可怜，被你爸吓得半死 她才把子宫拿掉
- I don't know what you ever saw in him. - Shh. Bad man.
真看不出你喜欢他哪点 小声点
Didn't tell you either?
也没通知你？
I didn't spend as much as Bernard, thank God.
好在没像伯那花那么多钱
- I'm sorry, Dad. - The way she looked at me.
爸爸，对不起 她看我的眼神
She loves you, really.
她仍旧爱你
You love each other. This is only a temporary glitch.
你们互相爱着对方 这种情况只是暂时的
Is it? I don't know.
是吗？我不知道
I don't know.
真的不知道
This is Penny. Geoffrey didn't get in touch with her either.
这是培妮，杰佛瑞也没告诉她
- I'm sorry? - Geoffrey didn't contact you either...
你说什么？
- Yes, he did. - Oh, right.
他有告诉我喔，是的
Lovely dress. Very exotic.
好漂亮的衣服，非常性感
Shame you couldn't bring your boyfriend. What's his name? David? Darren?
可惜你的男朋友不能参加 他叫什么？大卫还是达伦
Daniel Cleaver.
是丹尼尔
- Is he a friend of yours, Mark? - Absolutely not.
他是你的朋友吗？ 绝不是
I hope he's good enough for our little Bridget.
希望他配得上布丽姬
I think I can say with total confidence, absolutely not.
我可以很有信心的说，配不上
I'm sure he'd say the same about you, given your past behavior.
照你过去的历史 他也会说同样的话
- Sorry? - I think you know what I mean.
什么？ 你该知道我是什么意思
Looks like Auntie Shirley didn't get the message either.
看来雪莉姑母也没接到通知
I just really, really wanted to see a friendly face.
终于看到一张友善的面孔
Now, listen. I tell you what. I have an idea.
我有个好主意
Let me finish this while you go home and have a long hot bath...
你先回家洗个热水澡
and I'll call 'round, and we'll have dinner later, okay?
等我忙完 就打电话约你出来吃饭
- Is there someone here? - Not that I'm aware of.
有人在这里吗？ 我怎么不知道
Unless that Bosnian family's moved in again. Bastards.
除非那家波士尼亚人又搬进来
I'm sorry. Sorry.
对不起，真对不起
I'm going mad.
我在发神经
Listen, I am feeling really bad, actually.
其实我真的很过意不去
- I should have been there. - No, I'm sorry.
本该和你参加派对 不，我应该道歉
No, I'm sorry. At least I got a lot of work done.
不，我才该道歉 好在我做了不少工作
Just give me one more hour, okay?
再给我一个钟头就行了
Fine. That's fine. I'll go home and de-bunny.
那我就回家恢复我本来面目吧
And you know last night when I said I loved you?
还有昨天我说过我爱你
I didn't mean it. I was being ironic.
那不是真的 只是营造气氛而已
Good. I know.
我知道
Thank you, madam.
谢谢你
This is Lara from the New York office.
这位是纽约公司的萝拉
Lara, this is Bridget.
这位是布丽姬
Hey there.
你好
I thought you said she was thin.
你不是说她很瘦吗？
I was hoping that you would want to be a part of it.
我本希望你愿和我共渡此生
Listen, this is totally insane.
这实在太荒唐
I'm 36. It may be my last chance to have a child.
我已经三十六岁 也许是最后的怀孕机会
The male penetrates the female and leaves.
雄性在与雌性性交后就离去
Coitus is brief and perfunctory.
性交既短又马虎
For the female, all there is to do now is wait and wait.
从此雌性只有等待
We've had a very good response...
“泰迪最知道”
to the Teddy Knows Best teaser campaign...
这本书的促销活动很成功
and had various local radio bids for author interviews, which is good...
有许多当地电台想采访作者 这是好…
Stop that. I feel terrible.
别做报告了，我很难过
The thing is with Lara and me...
就是我和萝拉之间的事
- Well, you know. - No, you'll have to fill me in.
你是知道的 我不知道，你必须告诉我
The truth is we're the same, Bridge, you and me.
你我其实完全一样
We're two people of a certain age looking for the moment to commit...
我们不再年轻，都在找寻承诺
and finding it really hard.
却发现不易找到
And I just think that in the end...
本来以为你我之间
it's got to be something extraordinary which makes us go that extra mile...
说不定会有不凡的事发生 而让我们互订终生
and I think Lara being American or something to do with confidence...
可是萝拉也许因为她是美国人 又充满自信
and being so...
并且…
well, young, you know.
又年轻
We've become very close.
所以我们才会这么接近
You've only just met her. She flew in yesterday.
她昨天才来 你们不过才刚认识
Silly Bridget.
笨布丽姬
- You haven't only just met her. - No.
你们不是才认识吧 不是
No, I got to know her pretty well when we were in the New York office together.
当我在纽约办公室时 就已经认识
Oh, fuck.
真要命
There's no easy way to say this, but...
叫我怎么说
I wanted you to be the first to know that...
你是第一个知道的人
we're engaged.
我们已经订婚了
At times like this, continuing with one's life seems impossible...
此时若想为未来而奋斗 似乎不太可能
and eating the entire contents of one's fridge seems inevitable.
只好吃尽冰箱里所有的东西
I have two choices:
现在我有两个选择
To give up and accept permanent state of spinsterhood...
认命永远做个单身老女人
and eventual eating by Alsatians...
死后被狗分食
or not, and this time I choose not.
或不认命，我选择不认命
I will not be defeated by a bad man and an American stick insect.
我绝不会被英国臭男人 和美国竹竿女人给打倒
Instead, I choose vodka.
所以我选择伏特加
And Chaka Khan.
夏卡康的歌
Why do you want to be in television?
为什么你想到电视台工作？
Well, I've realized that I've become deeply committed...
我非常喜欢大众传播
to communicating to the public the up-to-the-moment and in-depth news...
而且希望把政治学 和生态学方面
both political and ecological.
最新、最深入的报导带给社会
What do you think of the El Nino phenomenon?
你对圣婴现象有何看法？
It's a blip.
很突然
I think, basically, Latin music is on its way out.
基本上 我认为拉丁音乐快落伍了
Why television?
为什么要到电视台工作？
Because I'm passionately committed to communicating with children.
因为我非常希望能和小孩沟通
- They are the future. - Do you have any children of your own?
他们是未来的主人翁嘛 你自己有孩子吗？
Christ, no.
天呀，当然没有
Sorry.
抱歉
So, why do you want to work in television?
为什么想到电视台工作？
I've got to leave my current job because I've shagged my boss.
由于和老板上床 所以必须离开
Fair enough. Start Monday. We'll see how we go.
很好，星期一开始上班
And, incidentally...
顺便一提
at Sit Up, Britain, no one ever gets sacked for shaggin' the boss.
在“英国注意”的时事节目中 没人因和老板睡觉而被开除
That's a matter of principle.
这是原则问题
Bridge, come on.
布丽姬，别这样
I know it's been awkward as ass, but there's no need to leave.
我知道事情棘手 可是不需要辞职呀
No, actually, there is. I've been offered a job in television.
有需要 我在电视台找到工作了
Television?
电视台？
And they want me to start straight away.
他们要我马上上班
So I've got to leave in about three minutes.
所以大约三分钟后就得离开
Just hold it right there, Miss Jones.
等一下，布丽姬小姐
I'm sorry to inform you, but I think you'll find that, by contract...
但是我得提醒你在合约上
you are expected to give at least six weeks' notice.
你必须在六个礼拜前通知公司
Yes. Well, I thought with the company being in so much trouble and all...
既然公司已陷入危机 少了个只知穿透明上衣
I want to hear this. Because if she gives one inch...
我倒要看看，如果她软化的话
I'm gonna fire her bony little bottom anyway for being totally spineless.
对于这种没骨气的女人 我也一样非开除不可
- What? - I just think you should know that...
什么事？
Just give me a minute, would you, Simon? Thanks.
塞门，给我一分钟
Righto, boss man.
没问题，老板
Lots of prospects for a person who...
将来应该会有很多机会
perhaps for personal reasons has been slightly overlooked professionally.
也许过去因为个人原因 而被忽视了她的专业技术
Thank you, Daniel. That is very good to know.
谢谢你这么说
But if staying here means working within ten yards of you...
可是留下来 就需要距离你这么近的工作
frankly, I'd rather have a job wiping Saddam Hussein's ass.
坦白的说 我宁愿替沙旦胡森擦屁股去
R-E-S-P-E-C-T Find out what it means to me
尊重的定义是什么
Take care of T-C-B
尊重就是完成任务
Sock it to me, sock it to me sock it to me
给我一点，给我一点
- Well, bye, everyone. - Just a little bit
大家再见了 只要一点
A little respect
一点尊重
All the time
永远地
Keep on trying
不断尝试
You're running out, fool
傻瓜，你已耗尽了
Just sod off.
看什么！
Hello and welcome to Sit Up, Britain, a current affairs show...
欢迎观赏“英国注意” 这个时事节目
Okay, everybody, it is bonfire night, and we are on fire.
大家好，今天是篝火之夜 而我们也热闹非凡
We have live fire station feeds from Newcastle...
有来自纽卡素、天鹅海
Swansea, Sheffield and Lewisham...
雪菲尔以及 路易斯翰等地区的火警实况
just poised for tragedy.
平静的报导灾情就好
BridgetJones, where are you?
布丽姬，你在哪里？
- I'm here, Richard. - Put on some more makeup.
在这里
I want you on camera. I'm thinking miniskirt.
我要你上荧光幕 穿上迷你裙
I'm thinking fireman's helmet. I want you pointing a hose.
戴上消防人员的头盔 要强调水管
I want you sliding down the pole. Then go straight to the interview.
当你从柱子滑下来后 就马上进行访问
Great. I'll do it.
好，我会做的
No problem. Fine. Right.
没问题，好的
So you drop into shot and then interview Chief Fireman Bevan.
你滑下来后 就访问消防局局长
Yep. Go, go.
好，开始
- Go? - Oh, no.
开始？ 不行
We're going to firefighters in Newcastle first.
要先播纽卡素的消防报导
Stop! Climb back up.
停止！快爬回去
Climb back up. On you in 30 seconds.
三十秒内就轮到你了
What is going on?
怎么回事？
She's supposed to be sliding down the pole, not climbing it.
她应该滑下来，而不是爬上去
- Go, go. Go! - Okay!
开始！好！
Oh, Jesus Christ!
喔，糟糕
We're out of time. Just wind her up.
没时间了，要她尽快结束访问
Well, that seems to be about all we've got time for down here in Lewisham.
好，路易斯翰的报导到此为止
Chief Officer Bevan, thank you very much.
毕文长官非常谢谢你
Excellent fire station.
非常出色的消防站
And now back to the studio.
现在回到摄影棚
Excellent. Am national laughingstock.
好啦，我成了全国的笑柄
Have bottom the size of Brazil...
屁股比西瓜还大
am daughter of broken home, am rubbish at everything and...
我是个家庭破碎、一事无成 而且…
Oh, God. Am having dinner with Magda andJeremy.
糟糕 我得和美嘉和杰米吃晚餐
The only thing worse than smug, married couple...
和洋洋得意的夫妻吃饭 已经很倒霉
Lots of smug, married couples.
这回要和一堆的夫妻吃饭 别提会多乏味
Right. Everyone, this is Bridget.
各位，这位是布丽姬
Bridge, this is Hugo and Jane.
布丽姬，这对是雨果和简
You know Cosmo and Woney.
这是卡斯模和王妮
- This is Alistair and Henrietta. - Hello.
这是艾丽丝坦和海尔达 哈罗
- Julia and Michael. Joanne and Paul.
茱丽亚和麦克，瑞安和保罗
And Jeremy's partners from chambers, Natasha Glenville and Mark Darcy.
杰米律师事务所的合伙人 娜塔沙和马克
- Hi there. - Hello.
你们好 哈罗
- Not in your bunny girl outfit today? - No.
今天怎么没穿兔女郎装？ 没有
We bunnies only wear our tails on very special occasions.
我们兔子只在特殊场合才出现
- Right, B. Sit yourself down. - Right.
小姬，你随便坐 好
Hey, Bridge, how's your love life?
布丽姬，你的爱情生活如何？
Still going out with that publishing chappie?
还和那个出版社的家伙出去
No, actually.
没有了
Never dip your nib in the office ink.
永远不要和上司睡觉
Right.
是的
You really ought to hurry up and get sprogged up, old girl.
老姑娘，你得快点结婚生子
Time's a-running out. Tick-tock.
时间不多啦
Yes, yes.
是的
Tell me, is it one in four marriages that ends in divorce now or one in three?
现在是四对有一对离婚 还是三对有一对
One in three.
三对就有一对
Seriously, the office is full of single girls in their 30s.
说实话公司里 年过三十的未婚女性一堆
Fine physical specimens, but they just can't seem to hold down a chap.
人挺漂亮，就是抓不住男人
Yes, why is it there are so many unmarried women in their 30s these days?
布丽姬，为什么会有这么多 未婚中年女性？
I don't know.
不知道
I suppose it doesn't help that, underneath our clothes...
我想就算在衣服之下
our entire bodies are covered in scales.
全身都在巅峰状态也没有用
I very much enjoyed your Lewisham fire report, by the way.
你在路易斯翰消防站的 报导很不错
Thank you.
谢谢
So, it didn't work out with Daniel Cleaver?
你和丹尼尔没在一起了？
No, it didn't.
没有
I'm delighted to hear it.
我很高兴听到
Look, are you and Cosmo in this together?
你和卡斯模是故意串通好的吗？
You seem to go out of your way to try to make me feel...
每次见到你
and you really needn't bother.
其实你不必费心
I already feel like an idiot most of the time anyway...
多半的时间就算没有消防柱
with or without a fireman's pole.
我已经觉得自己像个笨蛋
That'll be my taxi. Good night.
计程车来了，晚安
Look, I'm sorry if I've been...
对不起，如果我…
What?
怎么样？
I don't think you're an idiot at all.
我一点也不觉得你像白痴
I mean, there are elements of the ridiculous about you.
有时候你是很滑稽
Your mother's pretty interesting.
你母亲也很奇怪
And you really are an appallingly bad public speaker.
而且你的演讲实在恐怖
And you tend to let whatever is in your head...
你习惯性的想什么，就说什么
I realize that when I met you at the turkey curry buffet...
在咖哩火鸡餐会见到你时 我就发现了
that I was unforgivably rude and wearing a reindeer jumper...
那天我不但非常不礼貌 并且穿了一件驯鹿毛衣
that my mother had given me the day before.
是我妈前一天给我的
But the thing is...
但事实是…
What I'm trying to say, very inarticulately...
抱歉我口齿不清 我想说的…
is that...
就是…
in fact, perhaps, despite appearances...
实际上…也许…坦白的说
I like you very much.
我很喜欢你
Apart from the smoking and the drinking...
除了抽烟、喝酒
and the vulgar mother and the verbal diarrhea.
还有粗俗的妈妈 和唠叨不停的毛病
No, I like you very much, just as you are.
不，我喜欢你 就是你现在的样子
Mark, we really are making progress on the case in here.
马克，这件案子我们有了突破
Jeremy's had a most brilliant idea.
杰米有个很好的主意
Right.
好
I must go because...
我要走了，因为…
Well, bye.
再见了
"Just as you are"? Not thinner? Not cleverer?
就是你现在的样子？ 这样的身材、这样的脑袋？
Not with slightly bigger breasts and a slightly smaller nose?
这样的胸部、这样的鼻子？
Well, fuck me.
去他的
But this is someone you hate, right?
但这是你恨的人，是不是？
Yes, yes. I hate him.
对，我恨他
November 9. Weight: 138 pounds.
11月9日，体重138磅
Cigarettes:3. Birthday:33.
烟量三支，年龄33岁
The verdict in the Aghani-Heaney case is expected today.
今天是 阿汗尼－海尼案子的判决日
Get yourself down to the high court. I want a hardheaded interview.
你到法院去给我冷静采访
- You do know the Aghani-Heaney case? - Yes, of course.
你总该知道这个案子吧？ 当然知道
Big case...
大案件
featuring someone called "Aghani-Heaney."
主角是阿汗尼海尼
Or two people called Kafir Aghani and Eleanor Heaney?
也许是两个人 卡非阿汗尼和爱琳诺海尼
That's the one.
对，就是他们
She's a British aid worker. He's a Kurdish freedom fighter.
她替英国人工作 他是库德的自由斗士
The government want to extradite him home where he'll certainly be executed.
政府要将他引渡回国 后果可想而知
She's married to him, and they've fought for five years to keep him here.
她嫁给他，为让他留下来 已经打了五年官司
- Today is the decision. - That's exciting.
今天是判决日 真刺激
Yes, it is. So what are you waiting for?
没错，那你还等什么？
Am suddenly hardheaded journalist...
我突然变成冷静的记者
ruthlessly committed to promoting justice and liberty.
坚守报导正义和自由的原则
Nothing can distract me from my dedication to the pursuit of truth.
为了追踪真理 绝不会被任何事分心
Well, almost nothing.
几乎任何事
Right. I'll just pop to the shop quickly for some ciggies.
我到店里买包香烟
14Pfor the Polos and the packet of Wheat Crunchies.
我要薄荷糖和麦酥饼
- A packet of Embassy, please. - I'm sorry. I'm not quite fi...
一包香烟 对不起，我还没…
Good afternoon.
下午好
You like me just the way I am.
你喜欢我现在的样子
- Sorry? - Nothing.
什么？没什么
Bridget, we fucked up utterly.
布丽姬，我们完蛋了
Eleanor Heaney and Kafir Aghani have come and gone.
阿汗尼和海尼以经走了
Oh, God. I'll be sacked.
天呀，我会被开除
Did the others get interviews?
有谁采访到？
I don't know. I was having a slash.
不知道，我正在撒尿
- Actually, nobody got interviews. - So how do you know?
根本没人采访到 你怎么知道
Because I was defending him. I told him not to give interviews.
因为我是他的辩护律师 我叫他不要接受访问
Look.
你听着
I have a plan.
我有个计划
And action.
开始
Mr. Darcy, you were defending Mr. Aghani. You must be delighted.
马克先生，你一定觉得很光荣 能替阿汗尼先生辩护
Yes, well, Kafir Aghani has spent his entire life...
是的，阿汗尼先生终其一生
defending the basic human rights of his own people...
都在为他的人民争取人权
and today's verdict has been the result of five years of struggle...
五年来的挣扎 今天终于有了结果
by this woman, Eleanor Heaney, to save the man she loves...
这全是海尼女士的努力 为拯救她所爱的人而战
from an extradition order tantamount to a death sentence.
因为她知道引渡回国 无疑就是死刑的宣告
Right.
是的
And, Eleanor, over to you.
海尼女士请问你
Did you fancy Kafir the first time that you saw him?
第一次见到他时 你就爱上他了吗？
This has been BridgetJones for Sit Up, Britain...
这里是“英国注意” 由布丽姬为大家服务
with, let's face it, a bit of a crush now, actually.
说实话，是开始有些迷恋他了
Good afternoon.
午安
BridgetJones. Already a legend.
布丽姬，一个传奇人物
I feel fantastic, bombastic ecstatically astounded
我觉得美极了、棒透了 而且狂喜着
How a girl can really lose her grip
女人怎能失去支配力
I feel surrounded, confounded
我觉得困惑、冲动
Emotionally dumbfounded
而且吓呆了
Oh, joy, I am broadcasting genius.
太高兴了，我是广播界的奇才
Celebrating by cooking birthday feast for close friends.
所以决定做菜请好友来吃
Have sneaking suspicion am also genius in the kitchen as well.
因为我觉得 自己也会是厨房里的奇才
Tie flavor-enhancing leek and celery together with string.
用绳子把入味的 韭菜和芹菜绑起来
Right. String.
绳子呢…
Perfect.
很好
Finely slice oranges and grate zest.
橘子切薄片，把皮磨碎
Oh, bugger, bugger!
天呐！
Where the fuck is the fucking tuna?
鱿鱼在哪里？
This is BridgetJones for Sit Up, Britain, searching for tuna.
我是“英国注意”的布丽姬 正在寻找鱿鱼
- Hello, darling. - Hi, Mum.
哈罗，宝贝 嗨，妈妈
- I just wanted a bit of a chat. - Ouch!
我想和你聊一下 唉哟！
Careful, you ham-fisted cow!
小心点，你怎么粗手粗脚的
The thing is, darling, between you and me...
我想告诉你个秘密
I'm not entirely sure thatJulian isn't a bit of a shit.
我怀疑朱利安是个大混蛋
Mum, I haven't really got time right now.
妈妈，我现在真的没时间
I can't deny the sex is still very surprising.
其实，我们的性生活仍旧很棒
You know, the other night, quite unexpectedly...
有天晚上，我正在打瞌睡
I was just dozing off, and I felt this huge...
事先毫无迹象 突然有个很大…
Bye, Mum.
妈，再见
What time do you call this?
谁会来得这么早？
The door was open.
门是开着的
I came to congratulate the new face of British current affairs.
我是来恭喜你的，节目很成功
But I see I may have come at a bad time.
看来恐怕来错时间了
How's it look?
怎么样？
Great. It's...
很好，可是…
blue.
是蓝色的
- Blue? - No, but blue is good.
蓝色？ 不过蓝色很好
If you ask me, there isn't enough blue food.
市面上很少蓝色食物
Oh, shit. It must have been the string.
对了，一定是绳子
Oh, it's string soup.
原来是绳子汤
Oh, God. They're gonna be here any minute.
糟啦，他们马上就要到了
Don't worry. I'm sure they've come to see you and not...
别担心，他们是来看你的 而不是…
orange parfait in sugar cages.
为了糖粉里的柳橙果冻而来
- Let's have a drink. - Yes.
喝点酒吧 好
Happy birthday.
祝你生日快乐
Thank you.
谢谢
Did I really run round your lawn naked?
我真的曾经 裸体在你家草地上玩吗？
Oh, yes. You were four, and I was eight.
真的，你四岁，我八岁
That's a pretty big age difference.
那我们差得蛮多的
It's quite pervy, really.
似乎是很反常
Yes, I like to think so.
我也这么想
What are we going to do about this dinner, then?
晚餐该怎么办？
We can have blue soup to start...
就以蓝汤为始
orange pudding to end...
柳橙果冻为终吧
and, well, for the main course you have...
至于主菜，这里有…
congealed green gunge.
绿色胶状物
That is caper berry gravy, actually.
那是白花菜莓果肉汁
- Do you have eggs? - Yes.
有蛋吗？有
Right. Omelette it is, then.
那就做煎蛋饼
With caper berry gravy.
浇上白花菜莓果肉汁
You wouldn't by any chance have any beetroot cubes, would you?
有没有切小块的甜菜根
Minigherkin? Stuffed olive?
小黄瓜、橄榄？
No, Pam.
潘，没有
And besides, I'm busy. The gravy needs sieving.
加上我很忙，肉汁需要过滤
Surely not. Just stir it, Una.
吴娜，只要搅搅就可以
Happy birthday!
祝你生日快乐
- TV queen! - We're so proud!
电视女皇 我们为你骄傲
Bridge, you looked so fucking thin! You looked fantastic!
你瘦多了，而且美得冒泡
Hello.
哈罗
Are you joining us?
你和我们一起吃吗？
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
是呀，当然是
Excellent.
太美味
Delicious.
是很好
- Really special. - It's really very good.
非常特别 真的很好
Really, it's very nice.
的确不错
Mark, why did your wife leave you?
马克，你太太为什么离开你？
Eat up. Eat up. Two more lovely courses to go.
快吃，还有两道菜呢
Mmm, delicious!
嗯，真好吃！
I have to say, this is the most incredible shit.
真是不可思议
This is the worst of the three.
这是其中最糟的
It does remind me of something. It tastes like...
它的味道让我想起…
Marmalade.
橘子
Well done, Bridge. Four hours of careful cooking...
布丽姬，干得好 四个钟头的苦干
and a feast of blue soup...
做出了蓝汤
- omelette and marmalade. - Thank you.
煎蛋饼加橘子 谢谢
I think that deserves a toast. To Bridget...
我们应该干一杯，祝布丽姬
who cannot cook...
虽然不会做菜
but who we love just as she is.
但我们喜欢她 就是她现在的样子
To Bridget...
祝布丽姬
I'll go.
我去开门
Who?
是谁？
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
对不起
I'm obviously interrupting.
显然打扰你们了
What brings you here?
你怎么会在这里？
Right, yeah. I should have guessed, shouldn't I?
我早就该猜到
I'm Tom. It's really good to meet you at last.
我是汤姆，很高兴见到你
Listen, I just came to...
我只是来…
I thought you might be on your own.
我本以为你会一个人
What an idiot.
真是白痴
Excuse me.
抱歉失陪一下
I've been going crazy.
我快疯了
I can't stop thinking about you...
脑子里不停的想着你
and thinking what a fucking idiot I've been.
想自己是多愚蠢
Christ, is that blue soup?
天呀，那是蓝汤吗？
Yes.
是的
You know, that Sunday in the country...
在乡下的那个星期日
Come on outside.
咱们出去
It was all just going so fast...
事情是那么突然
the hotel and that weekend, meeting your parents.
旅馆、周末、还要见你父母
I just panicked.
我吓死了
You know me. I'm...
你知道我是…
I'm a terrible disaster with a posh voice and a bad character.
我是个表面说得冠冕堂皇 骨子里却缩头缩尾的人
You're the only one who can save me. I need you.
你是唯一能救我的人 我需要你
Without you, 20 years from now, I'll be in some seedy bar...
否则二十年后
And what about Lara?
萝拉呢？
Oh, over, over. Totally fucking finito.
彻底的完了
Dumped me.
被她三振出局
Dumped me when she realized I hadn't got over you.
当她发现我不能忘怀你时 就踢我出局了
I know you're thinking it's just a sex thing...
你一定认为只是性
but I promise you, whenever I see...
保证不是，每次在电视上
that skimpy little skirt on TV...
看到你那迷你短裙时
I just close my eyes and listen to all the intelligent things you'll say.
我就会闭上眼睛 仔细听你那智慧的谈话
I was thrilled that little Kurdish bloke was set free.
当听到库德那家伙被判无罪时 我兴奋极了
I've missed you a lot.
我非常想念你
I'm going now. Bye.
我走了，再见
Mark, stay.
马克，你别走
No, I don't think I will.
还是走比较好
Don't leave on my behalf.
别因为我的关系才走
It's about time you and I put this past behind us, don't you?
其实我们该尽释前嫌才对
At least stay for a birthday drink with me and Bridge, huh?
至少留下来和我及布丽姬 喝杯生日酒再走？
Good-bye, Bridget.
布丽姬，再见
Why are you here?
你为什么来这儿？
I just told you why I'm here.
不是告诉你了吗
Why was Mark wanker Darcy here? Oh, bloody hell.
为什么讨厌的马克在这儿？ 这个天杀的
Wait a minute. He's back.
他怎么又回来了
All right, Cleaver. Outside.
好，丹尼尔，到外面去
I'm sorry?
你说什么？
Outside?
到外面去？
Should I bring my dueling pistols or my sword?
是用枪还是剑？
All right. Hang on.
你等一等
I should have done this years ago.
早在几年前就该这么做了
- Done what? - This.
做什么？这个
Fuck! Fuck me, that hurt!
你疯啦，很痛的！
- What do you think you're doing? - This.
你在做什么？就是这个
Christ, not again.
别再打了
Fight!
打架！
What?
什么？
- Where? Where? - Well, quick! It's a real fight!
在哪里？ 快走，是真的打架
All right. I give up. I give up.
好了，我投降
Give me a moment, all right?
让我喘口气
Just let me get a moment's break here, okay?
让我休息一下，好吗？
Cheat! Cheat! Cheat!
使诈！他使诈！
I'll shin you!
我要踢死你
- Whose side are we on? - Mark's, obviously.
我们替谁加油？ 当然是马克
He's never dumped Bridget for some naked American.
他从没因为美国竹竿女人 而离开布丽姬
And he said he liked her just the way she is.
而且他还说喜欢她 就是她现在的样子
But he also nicked Daniel's fiancee and left him broken-hearted.
可是他曾抢走 丹尼尔的未婚妻，让他心碎
Good point. It's a very hard one to call.
没错，实在难以决定
I'm so sorry.
抱歉
- What are you doing? - Oh, God, I'm sorry.
你在干什么？ 啊！真对不起
I really am sorry. I will pay.
非常抱歉，我会赔你的
- Enough, Darcy? - Not quite, if that's all right by you.
马克，够了吗？ 不够，如果你不介意的话
- You broke my bloody jaw! - Happy birthday to you
你把我的下巴打烂了 祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear what's-his-name
祝亲爱的…他叫什么名字
Jesus.
天呀
- All right. All right. - Enough.
好了 够了
Enough.
够了
Wanker.
讨厌鬼
What is your problem?
你到底有什么毛病？
- My problem? - Yes!
我有毛病？不错
You give the impression of being all moral and noble...
你给人端庄又高贵的印象
and normal and helpful in the kitchen...
在厨房里也很正常、很帮忙
but you're just as bad as the rest of them.
但实际上和他们一样坏
Well, I can see that I've been laboring under a misapprehension.
看来我是被误解了
Very, very foolish mistake. Forgive me.
犯了不可饶恕的错误 请原谅
Let's go back upstairs.
我们上楼去
Come on.
走呀
We belong together, Jones.
我们本就该在一块
Me, you...
你、我
poor little skirt.
和小短裙
Right.
对
If I can't make it with you...
如果连你都搞不定
I can't make it with anyone.
那别人就更搞不定
That's not a good enough offer for me.
这种保证对我是不够的
I'm not willing to gamble my whole life on someone who's...
我不愿意把自己的将来
not quite sure.
系在一个 对未来仍不确定的人身上
It's like you said:
就像你说过的
I'm still looking for something...
我仍在寻找
more extraordinary than that.
那个非凡的人儿
Ding-dong merrily on high
快乐高到极点
December 25th.
12月25日
Weight: 140 pounds...
体重140磅
plus 42 mince pies.
再加上42个肉馅饼
Alcohol units:
酒精单位
Oh, thousands.
一千吧
Bugger off!
滚开！
Come on then, kids.
孩子们，走吧
This Baroque carriage clock is...
这个巴洛克风格的旅行钟
a particular festive favorite of mine...
是我最喜欢的
incorporating the "Hallelujah Chorus" from Handel's Messiah...
韩德尔弥赛亚中的 阿利路亚音乐
every hour, on the hour.
是它的报时音乐
I can't understand it. The man's actually turned red now.
奇怪，这个人怎么变成红色
Merry Christmas, Pamela.
潘，圣诞快乐
Well, I'm going to Bedfordshire.
我去睡了
- Night-night.
晚安 晚安
The thing is...
事实上
close up, he was almost purple.
近看他几乎是紫色的
You were such a lovely normal color.
你的颜色这么正常
He had a filthy temper.
加上他脾气很坏
And, well, the jewelry is fabulous and really very reasonably priced.
虽然珠宝不错，价钱也公道
I thought I might ask if...
我想问你
we could have another go.
能不能再给我们一个机会
Obviously with some effort on your part to pay a bit more attention to me.
我只希望你能多注意我一点
I do realize what I'm like sometimes.
我知道自己并不完美
It doesn't help that you and Bridget have your lovely grown-up club of two...
但当你和布丽姬成为死党
and always say, "What's silly old Mummy gone and done this time?"
老是笑我这里笨、那里错时 我真的很伤心
You used to be mad about me.
你曾经对我疯狂过
You couldn't get enough of me.
也曾需求无度过
What do you think?
你说呢？
I don't know, Pam.
潘，我不知道
I just don't know now.
真的不知道
It's been very hard.
我很痛苦
I'm joking, you daft cow.
骗你的，你这个傻女人
Pam, I just don't work without you.
没有你什么都不对劲
Awful!
你好残忍！
Lovely, lovely, lovely.
你真美
- Get back up those stairs. Get dressed. - What for?
到楼上去打扮一下 为什么？
The Darcys' ruby wedding party.
当然是为了去庆祝
"What for," indeed!
达西夫妇结婚40周年
Mark will be there. Still divorced.
马克也会来，仍然未婚
He's also still deranged. I'm not going.
也仍然怪怪的，我不去
Poor Mark. This is always a bad time of year for him.
可怜的马克 这段时间他最难过了
His Japanese wife left him on Christmas Day. Cruel race.
他的日本太太在圣诞节离开他 真是个冷漠的民族
Yes, but I'm not quite sure he didn't deserve it, actually.
说不定是他罪有应得
She ran off with his best friend from Cambridge.
她和他剑桥大学里 最好的朋友跑了
Total scoundrel, apparently. Best man at his wedding.
一个大恶棍 还是他婚礼的男傧相呢
Then Christmas Eve, Mark comes home early from work...
在圣诞夜，马克提早回家
finds the pair of them in a most unorthodox position...
发现他们一丝不挂
stark naked, at it like rabbits.
像兔子一样在性交
Just give me five minutes.
等我五分钟
Stop! Stop the car!
停，停车
Dad, get out. Too slow!
爸，你出来，你开得太慢了
- Dad, get in! Hurry! - What's the hurry?
爸，快进来 赶什么？
Not too fast.
别开太快
Bit snowy, isn't it?
下雪了，是不是？
Sorry. One moment.
对不起，失陪了
Thank you for inviting me.
谢谢你邀我来
I didn't. It must have been my parents.
我没有，一定是我父母亲
Hello, Bridget. Didn't know you were coming.
哈罗，布丽姬，不知道你会来
Mark, your father wants to begin ASAP.
马克，你父亲要尽快开始
Does he? Right.
是吗？好
Come on, Mark. Be helpful, please.
来呀，马克，拜托帮点忙
The caterers have totally screwed up. Does nothing work outside of London?
外烩做得乱七八糟 乡下就是不行
Apparently not.
比不上伦敦
I owe you an apology about Daniel.
我需要向你道歉 这要怪丹尼尔
He said that you ran off with his fiancee...
他说你和他的未婚妻跑了
and left him broken-hearted, he said.
害他伤心欲绝
No, it was the other way around.
不，完全和事实相反
It was my wife.
那是我的太太
My heart.
是我的心
Sorry.
对不起
That's why you always acted so strangely around him...
难怪有他的地方 你就表现的很奇怪
and beat him to a pulp, quite rightly.
还把他揍成烂泥 你做的没错
Well done.
揍的好
Can we just...
我们能不能…
pop out there for a moment?
去那边一下？
I just have something that I want to say.
有些话我想对你说
You once said that you liked me just as I am...
你曾说过 你喜欢就是我现在的样子
and I just wanted to say likewise.
我对你也有同样的感觉
I mean, there are stupid things your mum buys you.
你妈常买些无聊的东西
Tonight's another classic.
今天就是个例子
You're haughty and you always say the wrong thing in every situation.
你自大，任何场合都说错话
And I seriously believe that you should rethink the length of your sideburns.
还有你鬓角的长度 实在需要调整
But you're a nice man...
但你是好人
and...
而且
I like you.
我喜欢你
If you wanted to pop by sometime, that might be nice.
希望有空你能到我那边坐坐
More than nice.
非常希望
Right.
这样呀！
Crikey.
哇！
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生女士
could I have your attention for a moment, please?
大家请注意
Excuse me.
我得走了
Of course.
没问题
...wife and companion Geraldine.
娇拉汀是个好妻子、好伴侣
A toast to her, my wonderful wife Geraldine.
敬我的好太太一杯
To Geraldine.
敬娇拉汀
And we, in turn, have been blessed with our son Mark.
我们也有个好儿子，马克
He's always made us proud...
我们以他为荣
and we couldn't be prouder of him than on this particular day...
今天我们更为他骄傲
because I'm thrilled to announce...
因为我很兴奋的宣布
he has just been invited to be a senior partner...
纽约的亚培公司
in the firm of Abbott & Abbott in New York.
邀请马克成为他们的合伙人
He also, incidentally...
他也决定
takes with him his brilliant partner in law, Natasha.
请他美丽的拍挡 娜塔沙一起去纽约
And I don't think they'll mind, since we're amongst friends...
既然大家都是朋友 我就直说吧
if I say that, someday, this remarkably clever girl...
希望这位不可多得的女孩
is going to be something else in-law as well!
将来能成为我们的媳妇
I begged him not to say anything.
我求他别说的
So I ask you now to charge your glasses once again to...
请大家注满酒杯
Mark and his Natasha.
为马克和娜塔沙干杯
- To Mark and his Natasha! - No!
祝马克和娜塔沙
It's just that...
我觉得…
it's such a terrible pity...
太不公平了
for England...
尤其是对英国人
to lose such a great legal brain...
因为一个法律奇才…
- Is she pissed? - What?
她醉了吗？什么？
For the people of England...
就要离开英国
like me and you...
也等于我们当中
to lose one of our top people.
失去一位最杰出的人物
A top person, really.
真正杰出的朋友
Well, I better dash.
我得走了
I've got another party to get to.
还得参加另一个派对
Loads of single people.
全是单身
Mainly poofs.
多半是同性恋
Bye.
再见
Knew the signs, wasn't right
我知道情况不妙
I was stupid
曾经
For a while
那么愚蠢的
Swept away
把他
By you
从身边赶走
And now I feel
现在觉得
Like a fool
自己像个傻子
My heart's bruised
我心已碎
Was I ever loved by you
你曾否爱过我
Out of reach
虽已远去
So far
但至今
I never had your heart
仍未掳获你心
Out of reach
虽已远去
Couldn't see
“BJ的单身日记” 早该知道
We were never meant to be
“老姑婆与疯子” 我们本就不相属
Catch myself from despair
发觉自己在深渊中
I could drown if I stay here
几乎被绝望淹没
Keeping busy
只要每天
Every day
不断忙碌
I know I will be okay
就会没事
Yes?
谁？
Hi! It's us!
嗨，是我们
Great. Come on up.
快上来
Have we got the most fantastic surprise for you.
我们要给你一个大惊喜
- You're not going to sing. - Not that fantastic, sadly, no.
难道你要唱歌 傻瓜，不是那种惊喜
We've decided to take you to Paris so you can forget about everything...
我们决定带你去巴黎 好忘掉所有不快乐的事
particularly forget about Mark Darcy.
尤其忘掉那个马克
I can't believe you said what you said you said.
我不敢相信你说的话
I know! There goes my invite to the Darcys' next year.
在说过那些蠢话后 别想再去马克家
If he didn't leap over and whip you up in his arms, then sod him.
如果他不来拥抱你 那就忘了他
Yes. He's clearly the most dreadful cold fish.
没错 他的确是个可怕的冷血动物
Exactly. There's been all these bloody hints and stuff...
完全正确，给了他那么多暗示
but has he ever actually stuck his tongue down your fucking throat?
他有没有狠狠的吻过你？
No. Not once.
没有，一次也没有
- I think we should pack. - Passport, Bridget, and pants.
我们该准备了 护照和内裤
Yep. Pants.
对，内裤
Hurry up, Bridge. We're freezing our bollocks off.
布丽姬，快点，我们快冻死了
Yeah. Just the keys.
我在找钥匙
I'm stuck!
我卡住了
Come the fuck on, Bridget.
快点呀
Close the door.
把门关上
What are you doing here?
你怎么会在这里？
I just wanted to know if you were available...
我想知道 你愿不愿意陪我一同参加
for bar mitzvahs and christenings as well as ruby weddings.
往后无数个成人礼、洗礼 和结婚纪念日宴会的邀约
Excellent speech.
你那天讲得很好
I thought that you were in America.
我以为你到美国去了
Yes, I was, but...
我是去了，可是…
I realized I'd forgotten something back home.
发现在家乡有样事忘了做
Which was?
什么事？
I realized I'd forgotten to...
我忘了…
kiss you good-bye. Do you mind?
和你吻别，可以吗？
Not really, no.
好啊
So, you're not going to America, then?
那么你不去美国罗？
No. Not.
不去了
You're staying here?
留在这儿？
So it would seem.
看来是如此
No, I've never seen them before in my life.
这辈子从没见过他们
Are you coming to Paris or not?
你到底要不要去巴黎？
Not.
不去了
No fucking room anyway.
反正位子也不够
Maybe we should just go upstairs for a minute.
还是到楼上去吧
- Very good idea. - No room for him either.
好主意 也没有他的座位
Give me just a minute.
给我一分钟
Keep yourself busy. Read something.
你随便看看
Lots of very high-quality magazines...
有很多高水准的杂志
with helpful fashion and romance tips.
里面有服饰和恋爱指南
I'll be right with you.
我马上就来
Definitely an occasion for...
肯定是…
genuinely tiny knickers.
穿性感内裤的场合
Right.
这样呀！
Oh, shit!
完了！
Double shit.
全完了
Bollocks!
该死！
Oh, God.
倒霉！
- Wish me luck! - Good luck, crazy girl!
祝我好运！ 疯女孩，祝你好运
I'm so sorry.
对不起
I didn't mean it. I mean, I meant it.
那不是真的，我是那样写的
But I was so stupid that I didn't mean what I meant.
但写的并不是我的真意 我真傻
Oh, for Christ's sakes.
老天爷！
It's only a diary.
那只是本日记
Everyone knows diaries are just full of crap.
大家都知道 日记里全是胡说八道
I know that.
我知道
I was just buying you a new one. Time to make a new start, perhaps.
所以替你买本新的 好有个新的开始
Wait a minute.
等等
Nice boys don't kiss like that.
好男孩不会这样接吻
Oh, yes, they fuckin' do.
当然他妈的会
I'm delighted. They're both really good friends of mine.
我很高兴 他们都是我的好朋友
And I think it's great that they've found each other at last.
能互相找到对方，是个好结局
Brilliant, brilliant. This is Pauline, by the way.
很好，这位是宝琳
Paula.
是宝拉
How marvellous! Marvellous!
太美妙了！
Nice, healthy, well-built girl.
健康丰满的女孩
Can't be doing with a girl who's just skin and bone.
终于打败皮包骨的女孩
I like a woman with a backside you can park your bike in and rest a pint on.
我喜欢圆滚滚丰臀的女人
Malcolm.
马肯！
Well, obviously, I'm disappointed.
其实，我有点失望
Bitterly disappointed.
是非常的失望
But just 'cause someone's got a boyfriend...
不过就算有了男朋友
doesn't necessarily mean they won't...
并不表示他们就不会…
you know...
你是知道的
No, there's absolutely no bitterness...
我一点都不痛苦
no hard feelings.
或伤心
I just think it's great that in the same month that Bridge found Darce...
我很高兴在同个月里 布丽姬找到马克
I found Melani.
而我找到马莲妮
It's Alan.
是爱伦